# COLETTE O'SULLIVAN Architectural Technician and Interior Designer



# PROFILE:

I am a qualified architectural technician and interior designer with a first class honours degree in Interior Architecture and Design. In addition I am currently studying a Building Information Modelling with Revit Architecture course at Limerick Institute of Technology.

I would describe myself as a creative person with a passion for interior design and a great attention to detail, with experience working in both an architectural and engineering office. Within that time I expanded my understanding of how to develop a design from concept to completion, which in turn meant I could broaden my skill set. Moreover each office environment afforded me the opportunity to gain a comprehensive understanding of the importance of working effectively and efficiently both independently and within a team.

Following a recommendation from a college lecturer I had the opportunity to become an interior design tutor for the IDAI. I progressed from an online course tutor to the course director with a 4 year time-frame. Taking my industry experiencing and combining it with a good communication and presentation skill set meant that I could effectively design and deliver an interior design course.

#### COLETTE O'SULLIVAN

## Architectural Technician and Interior Designer

CONTACT:

phone: +353 87 9937890

email: coletteo32@gmail.com

## **EXPERIENCE:**

# Interior Design Course Coordinator - Course Director: June 2016 - Present

Interior Design Academy of Ireland: IDAI, Dublin 2

- providing tutor support and training to each interior design tutor both in-house and contact based
- development of assignment specific course content and supportive course material for each level of course offered
- approval of the assignment marking sheet and internal verification of the unit result awarded to a student
- providing general assistance and specific support to both online and classroom based student
- preparation of the classroom based PowerPoint Presentation for the higher national certificate and higher national diploma

Tutor: April 2014 - May 2018

Interior Design Academy of Ireland: IDAI, Dublin 2

online course tutor:

 interior design course - spanning from a 5 assignment certificate to a 30 assignment higher national diploma course

## classroom based tutor:

- BTEC accredited higher national certificate in interior design
- workshop preparation and presentation
- BTEC accredited higher national diploma in interior design including training in AutoCAD and SketchUp in addition with Adobe Photoshop

online course material:

- written course content including a document on critical study in Art and Design and specialist 3D material
- video tutorial for colour rendering material including colouring pencil and pastel in addition with pro-marker and watercolour paint

Educational Member of the British Institute of Interior Design



Architectural Technician: February 2016 - June 2016

T.G. Lenihan & Company, Engineering, Cork County

- working on one-off residential and medium scale commercial design in addition with community development
- 2D AutoCAD produced planning application drawing package and working drawing package for each project

## Training Coordinator and Project Manager: June 2012 - December 2014

Eolas International, Little Island, Cork County

- development of training material using articulate storyline: e-learning software for a
   Unilever global marketing research project
- management of a global employee group and monitoring of their data collection

Architectural Technician: December 2005 - May 2009

Kelly Barry O'Brian Whelan: KOBW, Cork City

- working on one-off residential and large scale commercial design in addition with mixed-use development
- 2D AutoCAD produced planning application drawing package and working drawing package for each project
- 3D SketchUP and Photoshop produced visual representation for mixed-use development
- land-use breakdown and shadow study analysis to determine the viability of the initial concept design of mixed-use development

 architectural and presentation model making conducted both in-house and in conjunction with an external model making firm

## **EDUCATION:**

**BIM with Revit Architecture:** presently undertaking Limerick Institute of Technology NFQ Level 6 Special Purpose Award

**Train The Trainer -** Training Delivery and Evaluation: 2016 – 2017 Merrion Square South, Dublin 2 QQI Level 6 Certificate Programme - Distinction

Graphic Design: 2012 – 2013 St. John's Central College, Cork City FETAC Level 5 - Distinction

**BA Interior Architecture and Design:** 2011 - 2012 Teesside University, Middlesbrough, United Kingdom NFQ Level 8 - First Class Honours

Higher National Diploma in 3D Design: 2009 - 2011 St. John's Central College of Further Education and Training, Cork City Edexcel Level 5 BTEC - Distinction

National Diploma in Architectural Technology: 2001 - 2004 Waterford Institute of Technology NFQ Level 7

## EXPERTISE:

- fluent in 2D AutoCAD and SketchUp
- Adobe: Photoshop Illustrator Indesign
- solid Irish building regulation and planning knowledge
- Architectural model making